General Manuscripts Miscellaneous Collection, 1502-2012: Finding Aid C0140
Manuscripts Division
- Hewes and Phillips, 1870; 1 box (Box 23)
  DS agreement between Hewes and Phillips and Frederick Fisher as an apprentice, 1 August 1870; "Special Regulations," DS signed by Jacob Fisher, Frederick's father, n.d. AM 11206
- Hewitt, Edward R., Class of 1889, 1944; 1 box (Box 23)
  TLS to Henry Savage recalling his student experiences, 20 July 1944. AM 12733
- Heydebrand und der Lasa, Tassilo von, 1818-1899, 1893; 1 box (Box 23)
  ALS to John Griswold White, 21 April 1893. AM 1998-104
- Hibben, Paxton, 1924; 1 box (Box 23)
  TLS to V. Lansing Collins concerning his war record, 10 January 1924. AM 11316
- Hichens, Robert Smythe, 1864-1950, 1899-1916; 1 box (Box 23)
  5 ALsS to various correspondents, 1899-1916; autograph signature, n.d. AM 18918
- Hiester, Joseph Muhlenberg, Class of 1825, 1835; 1 box (Box 23)
  ALS from A. G. Custier, 19 March 1835. AM 14415
- Higgins, Frederick Robert 1896-1941, 1925; 1 box (Box 23)
  3 ALsS to Harold Munro, 1925. AM 16161
- Higginson, Thomas Wentworth, 1823-1911, 1862-1879; 1 box (Box 23)
  ALS to "Dear Friend," 15 July 1862; ALS to "Dear Sir," 9 December 1879. AM 15168, 15606
- Hill, Samuel, 1765-1809, 1799; 1 box (Box 23)
  2 ALsS to Robert Rantoul discussing his engraving equipment, 20 and 24 September 1799. AM 92-25
- Hill, Thomas, 1829-1908, 1891; 1 box (Box 23)
  ALS to "My Dear Therese," 1 October 1891. AM 14895
- Hillard, George S., 1808-1879, 1863; 1 box (Box 23)
  ALS to Edward L. Pierce, 26 August 1863. AM 9694
- Hillyer, Asa, 1824; 1 box (Box 23)
  ALS to James Richards concerning the state of religion in NJ, 20 March 1834. AM 1312 Pyne Henry
- Hillyer, Robert Silliman, 1895-1961, 1933; 1 box (Box 23)
  "Intermezzo," AMs, poem, n.d.; "Pastoral XVIII," AMsS, poem, 1933. AM 15839
- Hilton, James, 1900-1954, 1934; 1 box (Box 23)
  TLS to J. Lionberger Davis, 24 October 1934; copy of TLS from Davis, 12 October 1934. AM 18300
- Hinkson, Katherine Tynan, 1861-1931, 1913; 1 box (Box 23)
  ALS to Walter, personal letter, 15 December 1913. AM 11797
- Historical Society of Princeton, NJ, 1960; 1 box (Box 23)
  Historical sites evaluation work sheets, 1960; printed materials and photographs relating to historic sites in Princeton, n.d. AM 22077
- Historical Society of Princeton, NJ, 1950; 1 box (Box 23)
  Report on Ewing and Harrison Streets, TMsS, 3 October 1950. AM 14358
- Hoar, George F., 1826-1904, 1872-1886; 1 box (Box 23)
  10 ALsS to Edward L Pierce, 1872-1886. AM 9695-9704
- Hoar, George F., 1826-1904, 1876; 1 box (Box 23)
  Resolution at Republican National Convention, result and vote, AD, June 1876. AM 9792
- Hoare, Prince, 1755-1834, undated; 1 box (Box 23)
  Autograph signature, n.d. AM 10161
- Hockley, Richard, 1753; 1 box (Box 23)
  Photostat of ALS to Thomas Penn, encouraging him to run for governor, 14 November 1753. AM 11849
- Hodge, Charles, Letters to William B. Sprague, 1855 October 16-1868 April 2; 1 box (Box 23)
  AM 2017-36
  Eight autograph letters by Presbyterian theologian Charles Hodge (1797-1878), in Princeton, New Jersey, to clergyman, editor, and author William B. Sprague (1795-1876), both of whom were 1819 graduates of Princeton Theological Seminary, regarding theological doctrines, ministerial appointments, the American Bible Society's new edition of the Bible, seminary alumni, a payment to Sprague for writing for the Princeton Review, the education of students at Princeton Theological Seminary, and other topics.
- Hodge, James L, 1862; 1 box (Box 23)
  ALS to Captain Marshall, 29 September 1862. AM 17829
- Hodges, Graham, 1979-1982; 1 box (Box 23)
  46 TLsS, ALsS, and Ds from various authors accepting or declining an offer to read and speak in "Conversations with Writers," 1979-1982. AM 90-69
- Hodges, Samuel, 1795; 1 box (Box 23)
  ALS to James Hodge, 8 March 1795. AM 12362
- Hodgson, Ralph, 1871-1962, undated; 1 box (Box 23)
  "The Bells of Heaven," AMsS, n.d. AM 19178
- Hofland, Barbara, 1770-1844, 1833-1843; 1 box (Box 23)
  ALS to Harness, n.d.; ALS to Hall, n.d.; ALS to Poublon, 11 November 1833; ALS to Howe, 18 January 1843. AM 19707
- Hogeboom, Stephen, 1744-1814, Account Book of Tax and Labor Records in Claverack, Columbia County, New York, 1786-1827; Hogeboom, Stephen, 1744-1814; 1 box (Box P-000148)
  Consists of an account book of tax and labor records kept by Stephen Hogeboom (1744-1814) from 1786 through his death in 1814 and continued by his descendants until 1827. The account book contains Columbia County, New York, tax records for the years 1786 to 1790, and detailed personal accounts for Hogeboom and the people he hired or conducted business with in the area surrounding Claverack, New York, from 1811 to 1818. These personal accounts include documentation of African American men and white women of the Claverack area who performed farm labor, cleaning, weaving, and other work for Hogeboom. While many entries document payment to laborers, some entires likely pertain to trafficked labor of people enslaved by Hogeboom's white neighbors. These entries generally document workers' names, tasks, and rates of pay. Some names of African American laborers whose work is documented in detail include Henry Constine, Thomas Carr, Joseph Hallinbeck, George Witbeck, Henry Borgardus, and Peter Vroman.
  The account book also includes an 1810-1813 account for future president Martin Van Buren, which deals with hay. Tax records indicate monies apportioned and received for various districts such as Kinderhook, Kings, Hillsdale, Livingston, Claverack, German Camp, and Hudson.
  Colonel Stephen Hogeboom (1744-1814) was a Dutch American colonist born in Columbia County, New York, to Colonel Jeremiah Hogeboom (1711-1784) and Janetje Van Alen (1720-). Hogeboom moved to Claverack in his youth and acquired large tracts of land from Claverack Creek to the Hudson River, which he leased, sold, and used for agriculture, and on which both enslaved and paid laborers worked. He served as a lieutenant-colonel of the Albany County Regiment during the American Revolutionary War and was later active in local politics, serving as a member of the 14th, 16th, and 19th sessions of assembly; the Constitutional Convention in 1801; and in the New York State senate for four years. He was also a judge, Claverack's town supervisor in the late 1780s, and ex officio on the county's Board of Supervisors.
  AM 2020-73
  African Americans -- New York (State) -- History -- 19th century -- Sources; Slavery -- New York (State) -- History -- 19th century.; Women -- New York (State) -- History -- 19th century -- Sources; Claverack (N.Y.); Account books.; Tax records.; Van Buren, Martin, 1782-1862
- Holcomb, Henry, Class of 1818, undated; 1 box (Box 23)
  Fly leaves from 2 books containing his autograph signature, n.d. AM 9802
- Holcroft, Louisa, undated; 1 box (Box 23)
  ALS to Miss Isola, in French, n.d. AM 77-157
- Holden, Edward Packard, 1871-1872; 1 box (Box 23)
  Grade report book from Lyon's Institute, 29 September 1871-16 February 1872. AM 16163
- Holden, Levi (1754-1823), 1780-1783; 1 box (Box 60)
  Captain Levi Holden fought at the battles of Trenton and Princeton and served as a lieutenant from June 1781 to November 1783, second in command of the Commander-in-Chief's Guard. Includes a fragment of a night-cap, purportedly knitted for Holden by Martha Washington, a list of the Commander-in-Chief's guards for August 1782, and a photograph of a portrait and brief history of Holden.
  Gift of the Osborne Stoddard family in memory of John Osborne Stoddard, Class of 1945.
- Holder, Christopher, 1659; 1 box (Box 23)
  Photograph of ALS, titled "A Warning from the spirit of the Lord to the Governor and Magistrates and people of the Massachusetts Bay," 1659. AM 2300
- Holliday, Frederick W. M., 1828-1899, 1877; 1 box (Box 24)
  ALS to George M. Johnson, 6 September 1877. AM 13366
- Hollingsworth, L, 1795; 1 box (Box 24)
  ALS to Cochrane Johnstone reporting state of affairs at Batavia, 20 October 1795. AM 11382
- Holmes, Elias Burton, 1870-1958, 1944; 1 box (Box 24)
  ALS to Robert Lindstrom, with TMs of a speech by Holmes attached, 21 November 1944; 2 copies of ALS from Lindstrom, 20 November 1944. AM 16788
- Holmes, Mary J, 1890; 1 box (Box 24)
  AMsS, quotation, 15 September 1890. AM 13475
- Holmes, Theodore, 1964; 1 box (Box 24)
  ALS to Frederick Fox, 13 March 1964. AM 21780
- Holt, Luther Emmett, 1855-1924, 1918; 1 box (Box 24)
  ALS to Mrs. Charles Richard Williams about food for children and also recalling her husband, 12 August 1918. AM 9615
- Hondley, William, 1790; 1 box (Box 24)
  DS, attestation as recruit in the Royal Lancashire Volunteer Regiment, 19 November 1790. AM 13598
- Honoré, Louis, 1923; 1 box (Box 24)
  ALS to Marcel Marion, 3 December 1923. AM 18259
- Hood, Samuel, 1724-1816, 1804; 1 box (Box 24)
  ALS to his tailor regarding a "pair of black breeches," 15 October 1804. AM 11302
- Hook, Andrew, 1932, 1962; 1 box (Box 24)
  18 ALsS and TLsS from American and European authors, 1962; printed program for the Edinburgh International Festival, 1962. AM 2000-102, 2001-26
- Hook, Theodore Edward, 1788-1841, undated; 1 box (Box 24)
  ALS to Mr. R. Bentley, n.d. AM 20649
- Hooker, Joseph, 1814-1879, 1859; 1 box (Box 24)
  Photostat of ALS to Capt. Thorn, 10 November 1859. AM 17484
- Hooper, Mary, 1701-1704; 1 box (Box 24)
  ADS, receipt, 28 December 1704; D, names of poor people to whom Hooper's money is distributed, n.d.; D, account of money received from her tenants, 13 November 1701. AM 1511, 1541, 1520
- Hooper, Robert Lettice, 1709-1785, 1777; 1 box (Box 24)
  ALS to Elias Boudinot regarding a complaint from Boudinot on giving the Prisoners of War too much freedom, 15 November 1777. AM 77-92
- Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964, 1932-1946; 1 box (Box 24)
  3 TLsS to Kemmerer, 1932-1933; TLS to Savage, 3 December 1946. AM 13267
- Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964, 1942-1944; 1 box (Box 24)
  2 TLsS (Xerox) to Mrs. Frances Adams Halstead, 5 September 1942 and 31 July 1944. AM 90-99
- Hope, Matthew Boyd, 1812-1859, 1839; 1 box (Box 24)
  ALS to I. M. Reade, 8 October 1839. AM 15252
- Hopkins, Gerard Manley, 1844-1889, undated; 1 box (Box 24)
  AMsS, poem and note, n.d. AM 22077
- Hopkins, John, 1803; 1 box (Box 24)
  ADS, record of sums received from "persons in the State of Virginia" for their subscriptions for "rebuilding Prince Town College," 21 June 1803. AM 367 Pyne Henry
- Hopkins, Mark, undated; 1 box (Box 24)
  Autograph signature, n.d.
- Hopkinson, Francis, 1737-1791, undated; 1 box (Box 24)
  ADS to David Rittenhouse, receipt for salary as Judge of Court of Admiralty, n.d. AM 10356
- Hopper, Edward W., Letter to George from St. Helena Island, South Carolina, 1862 September 25; Hopper, Edward W., 1839-1901; 1 box (Box 24)
  Consists of a seven-page letter from Edward W. Hopper (1839-1901), then a lieutenant in the Union Army, which provides a detailed accounting of Major General Ormsby MacKnight Mitchel's views on the need for the North to unite around the abolition of slavery. Hopper also discusses his hope that "increasing anti-slavery public sentiment" would enable the Lincoln Administration to "adopt a distinct policy" with regard to abolition. Hopper wrote the letter from Pope Plantation, St. Helena Island, South Carolina, to a friend back home in Boston, Massachusetts.
  Edward W. Hopper (1839-1901) was a lawyer, post commander and military governor in the South Carolina Sea Islands (1862-1863), and Treasurer of Harvard University (1876-1898). Hooper graduated from Harvard in 1859 and from Harvard Law School in 1861. He enlisted in the Union Army almost immediately after his graduation and was dispatched to Port Royal, South Carolina, in March 1862.
  AM 2021-37
  Purchased from L. & T. Respess Books in 2020.
  Antislavery movements -- United States -- History -- 19th century -- Sources.; Slavery -- United States -- Public opinion -- History -- 19th century -- Sources.; Saint Helena Island (S.C.) -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Sources.; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Military personnel -- Union -- South Carolina -- Port Royal -- Sources.; Correspondence -- 19th century; Mitchel, O. M. (Ormsby MacKnight), 1809-1862
- Hoppin, Augustus, 1828-1896, 1860-1862; 1 box (Box 24)
  9 ALsS to J. H. Richardson concerning problems of design and the illustrations for Irving's works, 1860-1862. AM 84-22
- Horace Imitated, 1741; 1 box (Box 24)
  "Horace Imitated," AMs, anonymous, 18 pp., 1741. AM 86-84
- Hornblower, Joseph Courten, 1777-1864, 1815; 1 box (Box 24)
  ALS to Tomas P. Johnson concerning case of Whiting and Watson vs. Morford, 9 February 1815. AM 858
- Hornblower, Joseph Courten, 1777-1864, 1811-1817; 1 box (Box 24)
  2 Ds, bills of sale of slaves to Hornblower, 1811-1817; 2 ALsS to Hornblower, 1812-1813. AM 20853
- Hornblower, Josiah, 1729-1809, 1806; 1 box (Box 24)
  ADS, last will and testament, 23 April 1806. AM 20853
- Horne, Mrs. Mary A, circa 1845; 1 box (Box 24)
  28 ALsS to Horne from her husband, Orran, regarding history and army life in the South, c. 1845. AM 12568
- Horne, Richard Henry (Hengist), 1803-1884, 1873-1876; 1 box (Box 24)
  ALS to Gallam, 9 June 1873; ALS to John H. Ingham, 8 March 1876. AM 17266, 20739
- Hornor, Mary, 1773; 1 box (Box 24)
  ADS to Jonathan D. Sergeant, receipt for board and lodging, 1 March 1773. AM 375 Pyne-Henry
- Hornor, Thomas, 1767-1834, 1788; 1 box (Box 24)
  ADS, receipt to Benjamin Guild for Joseph Kirkbride, 8 May 1788. AM 1771
- Horry, Richard, 1897; 1 box (Box 24)
  ALS to Professor Hurst, 28 November 1897; ALS to "Dear Sir," 16 November 1897. AM 15604
- Hosack, David, 1769-1835, 1831; 1 box (Box 24)
  ALS to Judge Buel settling his account, 20 January 1831. AM 98 Pyne-Henry
- Hosken, James Dryden, 1861-1953, 1903-1905; 1 box (Box 24)
  2 ALsS to H. Buxton Forman, 8 September 1903 and 16 February 1905. AM 22077
- Hosmer, Titus, 1736-1780, 1778; 1 box (Box 24)
  ALS to Richard Law, 1778. AM 12954
- Hotten, John Camden, 1832-1873, 1867; 1 box (Box 24)
  4 ALsS to John Lorimer Graham, February 1867. AM 83-83
- Houchen, William, 1887; 1 box (Box 24)
  ALS to George Brooks, 4 May 1887. AM 19136
- Houdon, Jean Antoine, 1741-1828, undated; 1 box (Box 24)
  Rubbings and notes on Houdon signatures. AM 19489
- Hough, Graham Goulder, 1908-1990, 1960; 1 box (Box 24)
  ALS to R. P. Blackmer, tutor or Christ's College, Cambridge, 24 May 1960. AM 22077
- Houghton, Richard Monckton Milnes, Baron, 1809-1885, 1873; 1 box (Box 24)
  3 ALsS to Mrs. Ward, 1873. AM 1999-30
- House, A. Humphrey, 1949; 1 box (Box 24)
  TLS to V. A. Halford, 10 November 1949; TLS (carbon) to House from Halford, 9 November 1949. AM 22077
- Housman, Alfred Edward, 1859-1936, 1911-1935; 1 box (Box 24)
  12 ALsS to S. C. Cockerell and others, 1911-1935. AM 14810
- Housman, Laurence, 1865-1959, 1897-1901; 1 box (Box 24)
  22 ALsS to Grant Richards, 1897-1901; ADS, receipt to Grant Richards, 24 January 1899. AM 20741
- Hovey, Richard, 1864-1900, undated; 1 box (Box 24)
  ALS to Dr. Burnett, n.d. AM 15071
- House of Lords, 1832; 1 box (Box 24)
  Engraving key of the portraits of the House of Lords, published by R. Bowyer and M. Parkes, 2 April 1832. AM 83-92
- How, Eleazar 1663-1737, 1730; 1 box (Box 24)
  ADS, bill of sale for a "negro boy named Robert" to Gershom How, 25 December 1730. AM 83-92
- Howard, Benjamin Chew, 1791-1872, 1837; 1 box (Box 24)
  ALS to Joseph B. Boyd regretting that he has no sample of the handwriting of Mr. Wint, 14 November 1837. AM 99 Pyne Henry
- Howard, Charles, 1808; 1 box (Box 24)
  ALS to "Sir," 1808. AM 12984
- Howard, Joseph, 1833-1908, 1882-1899; 1 box (Box 24)
  11 ALsS and TLsS from various correspondents to Howard, 1882-1899. AM 18284
- Howard, William B. H., Class of 1839, 1 box (Box 24)
  ALS, with typewritten copy, to his mother, Sarah T. G. Howard, 28 January 1839. AM 13050
- Howe, Captain G. R, 1915; 1 box (Box 24)
  TMs, narrative from memory and notes written while a prisoner of war in Germany, 1915. AM 18890
- Howe, Edgar Watson, 1853-1937, 1 box (Box 24)
  TLS to Mr. Dewar, partly about "A Story of a Country Town," 28 May 1937. AM 12189
- Howe, Roswell, 1828; 1 box (Box 24)
  ALS to Benjamin Olden agreeing to take one of his boys, 2 May 1828. AM 9581
- Howitt, Mrs. Mary (Botham), 1799-1888, 1832; 1 box (Box 24)
  ALS to John Darton, n.d.; ALS to James Fields, n.d.; ALS to T. Nelson, n.d.; ALS to Edward Moxon, 11 December 1832. AM 20179
- Hubbard, Elbert, 1856-1915, 1899; 1 box (Box 25)
  ALS to Mr. Halsey, 26 Juney 1899. AM 16712
- Huckings, Hester, 1698; 1 box (Box 25)
  ADS by Thomas Woodroffe and Richard Darkin, letter of administration of the estate of Huckings, 18 January 1698. AM 2092
- Hude, James, undated; 1 box (Box 25)
  DS, to the College of New Jersey, statement regarding lottery tickets, n.d. AM 8813
- Hudson, Claude Sibert, Class of 1901, 1927-1950; 1 box (Box 57)
  7 awards and citations, 1927-1950. AM 15073
- Hudson County Bar Association, 1915; 1 box (Box 25)
  DS, resolution on the death of president James B. Vredenburgh, 21 September 1915. AM 12188
- Hudson, William Henry, 1841-1922, 1903; 1 box (Box 25)
  ALS to the Hon. Mrs. Boutine, 30 June 1903. AM 14131
- Huger, Daniel Elliot, 1779-1854, 1844; 1 box (Box 25)
  ALS to Lewis J. Cist about an autograph from General Isaac Huger, his uncle, 28 March 1844. AM 257 Pyne Henry
- Hugg, William Jr., Class of 1786, 1782-1783; 1 box (Box 25)
  ALS to John Ladd Howell, 10 December 1782; ALS to Howell, friendly letter mentioning deserters, American Revolution, 12 March 1783. AM 9510, 9511
- Hughes, Charles Evans, 1862-1948, 1921; 1 box (Box 25)
  TLS to George Gray enclosing mimeograph copy of telegram from Zeballos Zolger to the Secretary of state naming the candidates for judges of the permanent Court of the League of Nations, 22 August 1921. AM 13084
- Hughes, Charles Evans, 1862-1948, 1907; 1 box (Box 25)
  TMs, copy of speech delivered before the Middlesex Club in Boston, 12 February 1907. AM 9899
- Hughes, Christopher, Class of 1805, 1839; 1 box (Box 25)
  ALS to Col. Preston, which references George Mifflin Dallas, class of 1810, 24 January 1839. AM 100 Pyne Henry
- Hughes, Langston, 1902-1967, undated; 1 item (Box 25)
  "In this life which ain't nothing.. .," AMsS, poem, n.d. AM 87-3
  Hughes
  James Mercer Langston Hughes was an American poet, social activist, novelist, playwright, and columnist. One of the earliest innovators of the literary art form called jazz poetry, Hughes is best known as a leader of the Harlem Renaissance.
  American poetry -- 20th century.
- Hughes, Langston, Typed Letter, 1934 May 15; Hughes, Langston, 1902-1967; 1 item (Box 25)
  One typed letter from Langston Hughes responding to a Mr. Langhorne who inquired about "the subject of 'The Attitude of the Southern Critical Public (white) to Negro Literature.'" This letter was written from Carmel, California, where Langston Hughes was preparing his first book, The Ways of White Folks, for publication. This letter documents Langston Hughes's response to some of the treatment he received from white audiences as a Black author and poet. He mentions his forthcoming book in the letter, and wonders what the response of the "Southern papers" would be to his new work, as "it contains some pretty sharp criticism of the prevalent white attitudes towards Negroes."
  Purchased from Max Rambod Rare Books in 2021 (AM 2022-052).
  African American authors -- 20th century -- Correspondence.; Authors -- 20th century -- Correspondence.
- Hughes, Richard Arthur Warren, 1900-1976, 1962; 1 box (Box 25)
  TLS to Rochelle Girson, Book Review Editor of the Saturday Review of Literature, with a statement about Hughes's "The Fox in the Attic," 19 January 1962. AM 80-79
- Hughes, Rupert, 1872-1956, undated; 1 box (Box 25)
  ANS to Thomas Brumbaugh, n.d. AM 87-24
- Hugo, Victor, 1802-1885, undated; 1 box (Box 25)
  "Un Mot sur George [John] Brown," Photostat and transcript of AMsS, n.d. AM 14707
- Hugo, Victor, 1802-1885, undated; 1 box (Box 25)
  "Un Mot sur George [John] Brown," reproduction of drawing by Hugo, n.d. AM 14707
- Hugo, Victor, 1802-1885, 1849; 1 box (Box 25)
  ALS to Due, 1849. Transferred from Theater Collection
- Hull, Hopewell, 1791; 1 box (Box 25)
  ADS, copy of his last well and testament, 10 January 1791. AM 1202
- Humboldt, Alexander, Freiherr von, 1769-1859, 1840; 1 box (Box 25)
  ALS to unknown recipient, 8 December 1840. AM 14564
- Humboldt, Alexander, Freiherr von, 1769-1859, undated; 1 box (Box 25)
  ALS to unknown recipient, n.d. Transferred from Theater Collection
- Hume, Joseph, 1777-1855, 1808; 1 box (Box 25)
  ALS to Charles Lamb, 11 January 1808. AM 77-161
- Humphrey, Heman, 1779-1861, 1828; 1 box (Box 25)
  ADS, testimonial for David March Smith, 5 June 1828. AM 8533
- Humphrey, Heman, 1779-1861, 1836; 1 box (Box 25)
  ANS, recommendation of Hudson River Seminary, with autographs of Gardiner Spring and Samuel Whittlesey, 25 January 1836. AM 791
- Humphreys, Edward Rupert, undated; 1 box (Box 25)
  "History of Free Masonry in Poland," AMs, n.d. AM 13330
- Humphreys, Anna Maria, 1773; 1 box (Box 25)
  D regarding the Parish of St. Cement Dane's, 19 March 1773. AM 21263
- Huneker, James Gibbons, 1860-1931, undated; 1 box (Box 25)
  AN to Vance Thompson on a calling card of Huneker, n.d.
- Hunt, Henry Jackson, 1819-1889, 1869-1888; 1 box (Box 25)
  2 ALsS to General Wainwright, 16 March 1869 and 9 August 1888. AM 86-122
- Hunt, Holloway, Class of 1794, 1793-1794; 1 box (Box 25)
  2 ALsS to the Presbytery of New Brunswick, 10 April 1793 and 21 April 1794. AM 18437
- Hunt, John, 1819; 1 box (Box 25)
  ALS to Samuel Parkes discussing the Examiner and his son, 11 December 1819. AM 86-83
- Hunt, James Henry Leigh, 1784-1859, 1853-1854; 1 box (Box 25)
  ALS to Lord John Russell, 28 October 1854; ALS to his publisher, Ollier, July 1853. AM 17983: 12541
- Hunt, Theodore Whitefield, 1844-1930, 1902-1911; 1 box (Box 25)
  6 ALsS to various correspondents, 1902-1911. AM 12413
- Hunt, Theodore Whitefield, 1844-1930, undated; 1 box (Box 25)
  Autograph signature, n.d. AM 17522
- Hunt, Ward, 1810-1886, 1853-1869; 1 box (Box 25)
  4 ALsS to various correspondents, 1853-1869; copies of 2 engravings. AM 18565
- Huntington, Benjamin, 1736-1800, 1783; 1 box (Box 25)
  ALS to Mrs. Huntington, 8 September 1783. AM 17885
- Huntington, Daniel, 1816-1906, 1857; 1 box (Box 25)
  ALS to Stephen Alexander concerning Alexander's portrait which he has been requested to paint, 20 May 1857. AM 11436
- Huntington, F. D. (Frederick Dan), 1819-1904, 1802; 1 box (Box 25)
  ALS to "My Dear Sir," 23 May 1802. AM 12716
- Huntington, Leveret I. F, 1815-1872; 1 box (Box 25)
  ALS to William Hall regarding "the work of the Lord in college," 11 February 1815; ALS to James McCosh referring to the work, 9 March 1872. AM 8791: 8782
- Huntington, Samuel, 1731-1796, 1777; 1 box (Box 25)
  ADS, receipt, 12 May 1777. AM 10357
- Hunter, Allan A., Class of 1916, 1947; 1 box (Box 25)
  Printed article, "A Clergyman Looks at the Movies," November 1947. AM 13570
- Huskisson, undated; 1 box (Box 25)
  Memoranda regarding negotiations with Mr. Otto (Lewis Guillamm) regarding an armistice between England and France, AMs, n.d. AM 92-89
- Hutton and Zabriski, 1832; 1 box (Box 25)
  DS, to William Berwick, cancelled check for $189 on the Chemical Bank, 23 July 1832. AM 8551
- Hyde, Douglas, 1860-1949, 1941; 1 box (Box 25)
  Poem, AMsS, 7 January 1941. AM 19211
- Hyne, Charles John Cutcliffe Wright, 1865-1944, 1893-1928; 1 box (Box 25)
  10 ALsS and 1 TLS to Colles and others, 1893-1928. AM 17045
- Illinois, 1867; 1 box (Box 25)
  D, summons for David Bettisworth, 18 August 1867. AM 2005-45